

# Victor Fernando Lopes de Souza

Engineering Student at CentraleSupélec

8 July 1999, Brazilian

+33 0665923179

victorfer.lopsouza@student-cs.fr

in linkedin.com/in/victorflosouza

github.com/victorsouza89

## About Me ——

Passionate for innovation and technology. Interested in approaching complex problems and grasping complex concepts.

Looking for a final year internship starting in May 2023.

Enthusiast of Mathematics, Stochastic Systems, System Modeling, Financial Markets and Blockchain

# Skills -

Multiple experiences on Python, LETEX, Matlab, Simulink, Linux, Git, R, Ladder, Java, C++, AutoIt and BASIC.

Experience on Web developing using PHP, HTML, CSS, SQL and JavaScript.

Experience on data analysis and neural nets using Pandas, Numpy, Tensforflow and Keras.

Good Mathematical Background and knowledge in Control's Systems, Automata and Discrete-Event's Systems.

Languages: Portuguese (mother tongue), English, French and Spanish.

#### Education

2022-2023	Université Paris-Saclay Master in Systems, Signals and Image Processing	Gif-Sur-Yvette (FR)
2021-2023	CentraleSupélec Engineering, with mention in Control	Gif-Sur-Yvette (FR) GPA: 3.65/4
2018-2023	UFSC - Universidade Federal de Santa Catarina Control and Automation Engineering PAM - Advanced Mathematics Program	Florianópolis (BR) GPA: 3.58/4 GPA: 3.86/4
2021-2022	Paris IV - Sorbonne Université Bachelor's degree in Philosophy	Paris (FR)
2014-2017	IFSC - Instituto Federal de Santa Catarina Engineering Technician in Electronics	Florianópolis (BR)

### **Work Experience**

2020-2021	Student Researcher in Neural Nets at EMBRAPII, in partnership with Central Energia (R& Worked on building, training, and evaluating LSTM noting the prediction of precipitation data for energy training training the prediction of precipitation data for energy training the prediction data for energy training tr	etworks regard-
2018-2021	Student Researcher in Algebraic Topology at IMPA (Brazilian Institute of Pure and Applied Mathe Research on advanced topics related to Geometric G	,
2018–2019	Calculus Teaching Assistant at the Mathematics Department, UFSC Developed PHP, Shell, BASIC and Kernel scripts to related to the management, monitoring and control of	
2016–2017	Intern as Web Developer at Oi S.A. (third largest telecommunication company in Developed PHP, Shell, BASIC and Kernel scripts to related to the management, monitoring and control of	automate tasks

### **Projects**

2022	Training Neural Networks with Kalman Filters Gif-Sur-Yvette (FR) Implementation of modern control methods for training Neural Nets and use of the Kalman filter as an optimization algorithm
2022	Exploring portfolio optimization methods, with BNP Gif-Sur-Yvette (FR) Construction, Implementation and Evaluation of different portfolio allocation methods
2022	System for inform on cancer, with Health Guide AI Gif-Sur-Yvette (FR) Testing of different recommendation algorithms for this purpose
2021-2022	Neural Nets: Attacks and Robustness, with SystemX Gif-Sur-Yvette (FR) Study and implementation of some attack methods on NN systems

#### **Honours and Awards**

2021	BRAFITEC, Merit Scholarship for Double Degree in France
2019	Qualified to Final Phase, OBMU (National University Maths Olympiad)
2018	Freshman Award, OEI (Organization of Ibero-American States)
2017	Silver Medal, OBMEP (National High School Mathematics Olympiad)
2016	Silver Medal, OBMEP (National High School Mathematics Olympiad)
2014	Honourable Mention, OBMEP (National High School Maths Olympiad)